<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sumit Singh</title><link>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sumit Singh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving Django projects to a new server</title><link>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/move-django-projects-to-new-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/move-django-projects-to-new-server/</guid><description>I keep migrating django projects from one provider to another. Everytime, I have to look up the same steps. So I decided to write them down here. It is a bit of a long post that contains various commands and sample config files, but I hope it will be useful to someone.
I&amp;rsquo;m assuming by now, you already created a new instance and is able to ssh into it.
Install/Update Server Dependencies sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get -y upgrade PostgreSQL Note: I install postgres inside the server, you can use RDS or some external service as well.</description></item><item><title>Install and Manage your own PostgreSQL Server</title><link>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/install-and-manage-postgres/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/install-and-manage-postgres/</guid><description>Commands which I use to install and manage my own PostgreSQL server.
Install the dependencies to use Postgres with Python/Django
sudo apt-get -y install build-essential libpq-dev python3-dev Install Postgres Server
sudo apt-get -y install postgresql postgresql-contrib Create a new user sudo -u postgres createuser --interactive After running the above command, you will be prompted something like this:
Enter name of role to add: new-user Shall the new role be a superuser?</description></item><item><title>Install Python</title><link>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/install-python-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sumit4613.github.io/posts/install-python-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>On new Ubuntu servers, Python 3.10 is installed by default. But if you want to install a specific version of Python, this post shows you how.
Run the following commands with sudo or root user.
Install the prerequisites sudo apt-get update sudo apt install software-properties-common Update the sources sudo add-apt-repository ppa:deadsnakes/ppa When prompted press Enter to continue:
Press [ENTER] to continue or Ctrl-c to cancel adding it. Install Python 3.8 sudo apt-get -y install python3.</description></item></channel></rss>